所以  系统是如何知道地图软件能够接受它的指令的呢
So, how did the system know that the Maps
地图软件的每个活动
app could handle this Intent? The activity within the
都会包含一个类似载货单接口的指令过滤器
Maps app included an intent filter like this one
在数据库里有一个地图方案  它指明了
within its manifest entry. It indicates that the Maps
地图软件能执行的预行为
app is capable of performing this view action on
针对你的活动  你可以
all data which has a geo scheme. You can
使用指令过滤器定义一个它们能胜任的行为
use intent filters for your activities to define the
但任意地  这类数据
actions they're capable of performing, and optionally, the kind
要能顺利执行  所以
of data that they can perform it on. So,
当你使用一个暗示指令去写地址或者
when you use an implicit intent to address or
请求开始一个活动  更多就像你和凯瑟琳以及开放天气地图域名链接在做这件事一样
request to start an activity, much like you did
安卓解决这类请求的方法
with Catherine and the openweathermap.org link, Android resolves this request
是通过检查每个活动的指令过滤器
by checking the intent filters of every activity that's
直到这些被安置在设备上的活动找到可能的最佳
installed on the device until it finds the best possible
匹配  如果有多种匹配方式  就根据网址域名的实际情形
match. If multiple activities match, as in the case
使用者有选择的机会
with the web url, the user is given a choice.